好 我看看...
Okay, let's see...
帮我去拿一瓶特级初榨[处女]
Oh, could, you grab me an extra virgin...
我觉得有一个作为祭品就够了
I think one's enough for the sacrifice.
橄榄油 菲尔
Olive oil, Phil.
笑一个 多逗啊
Come on. That's funny.
确实比你的三明治说唱好笑
Oh, it's funnier than your freestyle "Sandwich rap."
姑娘 你个疯子
Girl, you crazy.
跟我一起购物最有趣了
I'm mad fun to shop with.
徘徊在两个全麦面粉货架之间
Trapped in between two whole wheat slices.
唯五香熏牛肉和芝士与我相伴
Pastrami and swiss are my only vices.
亲爱的 我的鞋 看着点 真是的
Sweetie, my shoe. Come on. Jesus. God.
你好
Hello.
Hi.
路障
Oh, roadblock.
-哔哔哔 -不好意思
- Beep beep! - Pardon me.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
事实上 有事
Actually, not okay.
事儿大了
Not okay.
亲爱的 你是不是又从底下抽罐头了
Honey, did you pull from the bottom again?
开胃菜之后
So after hors d'oeuvres,
我们把大家召集到客厅宣布这个消息
We'll bring everyone in here to share the news.
我们叫全家人明晚过来聚餐
We're having the family over tomorrow night
告诉大家我们打算再收养一个小孩
to tell them we're planning on adopting a new baby.
是的 而且我们都同意
Yes, and we both agreed
这次选择低调一点的方式宣布这个消息
to--to go a little more low-key with the announcement this time.
*来听听爱子的声音吧*
*Let's hear it for the boy ...*
我就问问清楚 这是低调吗
Okay, just to be clear, this is low-key?
就一条横幅
It's a banner
还有些轻音乐伴奏 米奇尔
And just some light musical accompaniment, Mitchell.
我不能再低调了
I don't have a lower key.
再说了 这是个欢乐的场合
Besides, this is a happy occasion.
对吧 莉莉
Am I right, lily?
你马上就有个弟弟了 是不是很开心
Aren't you excited to get a new baby brother?
不 我讨厌宝宝
No! I hate the baby!
我们遇到了一点小问题
We are having a slight issue
暂时尚未说服莉莉同意我们收养个儿子
getting Lily on board with the adoption.
"我讨厌宝宝"
"I hate the baby."
"不要新宝宝"
"No new baby."
"我想弄死那宝宝"
"I wanna make the baby dead."
我们不是说好了不提这句的吗
I thought we weren't gonna share that one.
我 我 我只是希望问题出在
I-I-I just hope that the problem is
她只是跟其他小孩相处太少了
she hasn't spent much time with any babies.
所以我们想了个好主意
So we thought it would be a great idea
如果有个孩子陪着她 她就会知道多有乐趣了
to show her how much fun it'll be to have one around.
他真可爱
oh, he is so cute!
是的 他从不哭闹
Yeah, and he never cries.
真的是没哭过 真是有点怪了
Literally never. It's actually a little weird.
不 这没什么
Oh, no, that's not weird.
我姐姐出生时全部牙齿已经长齐了
My sister was born with a full set of teeth.
乱说的 没那回事
Yeah, that never happened.
没 你不信 你该看看她的婴儿床
No? Really? You should've seen her crib.
就像是海狸睡过 被咬的乱七八糟
It looked like beavers lived there.
这是莉莉吗
Oh, is this Lily?
对 是她 亲爱的 跟小家伙问好
oh, yes, it is. Hey, honey. Say hi to the baby.
这是我爸爸
My daddy!
起码小孩儿不哭的问题是解决了
Okay, so that's one problem solved.
再见 再见
Bye! See you soon!
或者再也不见
Or never.
小卡 我有点被莉莉的举动吓坏了
Cam, I'm a little freaked out about what Lily did.
想太多了 她都没怎么碰到他
Oh, please. She barely touched him,
他就毫无缘由地大哭大闹
And he went from zero to big crybaby.
我们现在是要让这个家多个小成员
We're talking about bringing another child into this house.
莉莉对你的占有欲这么强怎么能行
How's that gonna work with Lily being so possessive of you?
我怎么听到指责的语气
Why am I hearing an accusatory tone?
拜托 你得承认你对他过于溺爱了
Oh, come on. You have to admit that you do coddle her.
我不会为爱我们的女儿而道歉
I will not apologize for loving our daughter.
我不是在批评你
I'm not criticizing.
我不只是在批评你
I'm not only criticizing,
我的意思是我们要让莉莉更独立一些
But we did talk about giving Lily a little more independence.
没错 所以我们才把她送去幼儿园的啊
Yeah, which is why we put her in preschool.
对 但你却舍不得把她留在那儿
Yes, but you can't bear to leave her there.
你总是早早地去接她
You always pick her up early.
没有的事
That is ridiculous.
好 好
Okay. Okay.
莉莉 亲爱的
Lily, honey,
今天爸爸提前去幼儿园接你了吗
Did daddy pick you up early from preschool today?
没有
No.
"就此结案"
Case closed.
我根本没去上学
We didn't go.
"重新立案"
Case opened.
我们去购物了
We went shopping.
好了好了
That's enough.
我们买了父女帽
We bought matchy hats.
你得回房去了
you are going to your room.
你也跟进去干嘛
You're both going to her room.
我们常常黏在一起吗 是的
Do we spend a lot of time together? Yes.
我们父女感情甚密吗 当然
Do we have a special bond? Absolutely.
但说我过于溺爱她 远超过其他慈母仁父
But do I coddle her more than any other loving parent?
也许是吧
It's possible.
为了莉莉 我应该少一点溺爱
And for Lily's sake, I should probably work on that.
不 你给我冷静
No, you calm down!
有人指责我的曼尼偷东西我就这样说话
This is how I talk when somebody accuses my Manny of stealing.
-是谁 -是校长
- Who is that? - It's the principal.
他说曼尼偷了个什么女生的小吊坠
He's saying that Manny stole some girl's locket.
你以为所有的哥伦比亚人都是罪犯
What, do you think that all colombians are criminals,
因为哥伦比亚领带
because a colombian necktie
在全球都是暴力的标志吗
is a symbol of violence all over the world?
不不 我不是在恐吓你
No, no, I'm not threatening you.
好的 我接受你的道歉
Okay. Apology accepted.
没有 我提到领带并没有什么特殊意思
No, I didn't mean anything about the necktie.
我只是 我只是随便举个例子说说
I just--I was trying to make a point.
你能不能笑得不那么大声
Could you "L." a little less "O.L."
你没看见我在干嘛吗
Don't you see what I'm trying to do here?
孤独地死去吗
Die alone?
姑娘们 吃饭了
Girls, dinner!
为什么卢克有自己的房间
You know, why does Luke get his own room,
我却要和你住一间 我再也受不了了
and I still have to share with you? I can't take it anymore.
我也是 即使只还有一年而已
Me either, even if it is just for one more year...
到时我就去读大学
when I leave for college.
是确定只忍受一年 还是等你上大学的时候
It is one more year or when you leave for college?
那完全两码事 能不能上大学还不一定呢
Because those happen to be two different things.
我听到罐头堆中传来个小声音
So I hear this little voice coming from the cans
好像是在喊
And it's like...
"救救我 我被桃子淹没了"
"Help! I fell in the peaches!"
太是妈妈的风格了
that's mom!
-太欢乐了 -绝对欢乐
- Hilarious! - So hilarious.
我想着 是克莱尔在喊吗
I'm like, "Claire?"
也许你该告诉他们
You might wanna tell them that it was you
是你把我推过去的
Who pushed me into the peaches in the first place.
又来了 我当时几乎都没靠近你
This again? I wasn't even near you.
不 你就在我旁边 你把我撞到推车上
Yes, you were! You knocked me with the cart.
那完完全全是你的错
It was completely your fault.
让我们求同存异行吗
Well, let's just agree to disagree.
不行 我现在全是"异见"
No. I-I disagree to disagree.
负负得正了
Then you agree.
不 不 没有 我是对的
No. No, I don't, because I'm right.
好吧 克莱尔 你是对的
Okay, claire. You're right.
一如往常
as usual.
-不 我就是对的 -一直都是
- No, I am right. - like always.
行了 如果我真错了 我会承认的
Stop it. When I am wrong, I admit it.
从未发生
which is never.
好吧 好吧
Fine. Fine.
你今晚有点不正常啊 曼尼 出什么事了吗
You're a little jumpy tonight, Manny. Anything wrong?
没有 我刚想
No. Well, I'm just gonna--
孩子 坐下
Have a seat, kid.
也许是我的错觉
You know, maybe it's me,
但我感觉你今天有点古怪
But I thought you were kinda squirrelly tonight, you know,
在你妈妈接到校长电话之前
Before when your mom was on the phone with the principal.
我感觉你好像想说些什么
Almost like you wanted to say something...
但你却说不出口
but you just couldn't.
现在有什么想说的吗 曼尼
anything you wanna say now, Manny?
没有 我没什么好说的
No. I have nothing to say.
你确定
You sure about that?
好好想想
Think real hard.
我能喝杯水吗
Could I get a glass of water?
那个姑娘的小吊坠 是你拿的 对吧
That girl's locket-- you took it, didn't you?
-对不对 -是的 是我拿的
- Didn't you? - Yes.Yes, I took it.
-我不是故意的 -我不想听你的借口
- I didn't mean to. - I don't wanna hear any excuses.
你去告诉你妈妈 然后把问题解决了
You're gonna tell your mom, and you're gonna set this right.
明白了吗
Do you understand?
好的 走吧
All right, get out of here.
还有一件事
Just one more thing.
你没有...
You're not, um...
你偷那个吊坠不是为了自己戴吧
You're not wearing that locket, are you?
没有 当然没有
No. Of course not.
那是女孩戴的 我干嘛要戴
It's a girl's. Why would I want to wear it?
我就随口一问
It's no reason.
妈妈 快点 我不想迟到
Mom, hurry up! I don't want to be late for school.
你没告诉她是吧
You didn't tell her,did you?
为什么今早这么着急
What's the hurry this morning?
你们爷俩的表情是怎么回事
Okay, what's with the looks?
就像在看默片一样
It's like a silent movie in here. Okay.
我跟在一个叫阿丽莎的姑娘后面 她要搬家了
I was walking behind this girl Alicia, who's moving away,
我好不容易鼓起勇气想要她的新地址
And I was working up the courage to get her new address
这样我就能给他写信了
So I can write her.
我比较擅长用文字表达自己
I express myself a lot better on paper than--
别太忽悠 孩子
Ticktock, kid.
好吧 她的吊坠掉了 然后我就捡起来了
Well, she dropped her locket, and I picked it up,
但是她一直在走 我
But she kept walking, and I...
你偷了吊坠
You stole the locket.
我还告诉校长
After I told the principal
你绝不会做出这样的事情
That you could have never done something like that,
我还用哥伦比亚领带威胁他
And I threaten him with the colombian necktie!
为什么 曼尼
Manny, why?
别担心 他偷来不是因为自己想戴
Don't worry. It wasn't 'cause he wanted to wear it.
我只是想留个纪念
I thought I could keep it as something to remember her by.
但是后来你冲着维克斯先生大喊
But then you were yelling at Mr. Vickers,
我就不敢告诉你了
And I-I was just too scared to tell you.
上车
Go to the car.
-我真的很抱歉 -快去
- I'm really sorry. - Go.
他怎么会做出这样的事
Why would he do something like that?
他已经够怪异的了
It's bad enough that he's the boy
爱吹排笛 体型臃肿 没事儿就吟诗作对
with the pan flute and the puffy shirts and--and the poems.
现在还成了珠宝大盗
Now he's the jewelry thief.
已经算上升个等级了
Might be an upgrade.
杰 这可不好笑
Ay, Jay, this is not funny.
这种污点终生都洗不掉啊
Those things stick to you.
我表妹洛萨·玛丽娜
My cousin Rosa Marina--
她14岁的时候 偷了东西 从那之后
When she was 14, she stole something, and after that,
所有人都把她当成是偷车贼
Everybody thinks of her as the girl who steals cars.
她偷了一辆车
She stole a car?
不止一辆
Cars.
但她一旦被贴上那样的标签 她还能干什么呢
But after she got that label, what else could she do?
听着 你不能控制孩子的想法
Listen, you can't control what kids think,
但是你能让他从这次的事件中得到教训
But you can make sure he learns from this.
你带他去校长办公室
You take him to the principal's office,
他承认错误 然后就不会再犯
He owns up to it, he never does it again.
好吧 好吧
Okay. Okay.
他是怎么想的
But what was he thinking?
这都不是真金的
This is not even real gold.
不可能 海莉 这是我的主意 我要这间
No way, Haley! It was my idea! I'm taking this room!
痴心妄想
Over my dead body!
我要定了这间房
This is going to be my room,
你连想也别想
And there's nothing you can do about it!
有点过吧
Seriously?
你们在吵什么
What are you guys fighting about?
我们都觉得
Okay, so we both think
这里做卧室再合适不过了
That this would make a totally awesome bedroom.
但只有一个人能拥有它
But only one of us can have it.
你不觉得应该是我吗
Don't you think it should be me?
是你的才怪 应该是我的 对吧 卢克
Oh, so not. It should be me. Right, Luke?
你们为什么想搬进阁楼来
why do you guys wanna move into the attic?
你是说"顶层公寓"吗
Oh, you mean "The penthouse"?
隐私得到极大保护的独层公寓噢
With all the privacy of being on its very own floor?
确实不错
It is kinda cool.
我不是白痴
I'm not an idiot.
我知道她们在打什么鬼主意
I knew what they were up to,
不过我也一直想挪个窝
but I've been wanting to move for a while.
有一队蚂蚁
There's a line of ants
正在向我衣橱里万圣节的糖袋子进军
going to a trick-or-treat bag in my closet,
我可不希望它们吃腻了糖
and I don't want to still be there
就拿我当肉宰割
when they get tired of candy.
早上好 小公主
Good morning, princess.
早上好 莉莉
Good morning, Lily.
真可爱 米奇尔
Very adorable, Mitchell,
但是 今天早上对我来说太艰难了
but I'm having kind of a rough morning,
爹地 抱抱
Daddy, up.
对不起 莉莉 好日子到头了
I'm sorry, Lily, those days are over.
这是你的午饭
Now here's your lunch.
去把你的书包拿来 我们马上出发
Go get your bag. We will be leaving shortly.
小卡 你也不用对她这么冷冰冰啊
Cam, you don't have to ice her out completely.
你以为我愿意这么做吗
Do you think I'm enjoying this?
但是我得让她在新东西来之前 摆脱对我的依赖
But I need her to detach from me before the new thing comes
不然的话 鬼知道她会对他怎么样
or who knows what she'll do to it.
你为什么把"宝宝"说成"东西"
Why are you saying "Thing" Instead of "Baby"?
干掉新宝宝
Kill the new baby.
我知道这么做很难受
Oh. Um, look, I-I-I know this is hard,
我也很欣赏你的挽救措施
but I really appreciate what you're doing.
相信我
And believe me,
看着你受此煎熬 我也很难过
I take no pleasure in seeing you suffer like this.
我其实有点偷着乐
I take a little pleasure.
主要是因为 在为人父母这方面上
No, but there--there are very few parenting issues
我向来都表现比他糟糕
where I come out on top.
我跟家人有点疏远 我工作太忙了
You know, I'm distant. I work too much.
我给莉莉编的法式辫子像乱麻
My French braiding is "Sloppy."
终于 有些事不是我的错了
Finally, you know, something that isn't my fault.
准备好了
Ready.
你可不可以把她抱进车里
Could you please just go put her in her car seat
我需要淡定一下
while I compose myself?
好的 那个 小卡
All right, you know what, Cam?
不如我上班时候顺便送她去幼儿园吧
Why don't I just take Lily to preschool on my way to work?
那敢情儿好
I think that would be best.
出发之前让我来给你弄一份冰沙
Let me just whip up a smoothie for you before you go.
我要按那个按钮 爹地
I push the buttons, daddy.
"好呀"
You certainly do.
你觉得校长会怎么处理我
What do you think the principal's going to do to me?
我是初犯
I am a first-time offender.
这下好了 我还迟到了 罪加一等
Oh, great. Now I'm tardy. Strike two.
曼尼 态度积极点
Manny, think of this in a positive way,
-把它当成你的"哈哈"时刻 -什么意思
- Like it is your "Ha ha" moment. - What does that mean?
意思是 将来有一天你会一笑置之的
That means that one day, you're gonna laugh about it.
我当时就该把那该死的吊坠还给阿丽莎的
Ah, I should've just given that stupid necklace back to Alicia
那时候她就站在她的储物柜旁边
When she was standing right next to her locker.
这是我一生中最糟糕的一天
This is the worst day of my life,
明天也是
till tomorrow... Oh.
还有以后的每一天
And every day after that. Oh.
走吧 妈妈 让我们快点解决这件事
Come on, mom. Let's get this over with.
-等一下 -怎么了
- Wait. - What?
你说哪个是她的储物柜 这个吗
Which one did you say that it was her locker? This one?
是的 那个闻起来像玫瑰精油的味道
Mm-hmm. The one that smells like rose oil.
妈妈
Mom?
把好风
Keep the lookout.
现在 向我保证你再也不做这种事了
Now promise me that you will never, ever do anything dishonest again.
我保证
I promise.
很好 我养的儿子可不是珠宝大盗
Okay, because that's not the way I raised you.
对杰一定要守口如瓶 好吗
Don't tell Jay anything, okay?
-早上好 莉莉 -好了 莉莉
- Hi, Lily. - All right, Lily.
玩的开心 甜心儿
Hi. Have fun, sweetheart.
再见
Bye.
她真可爱
She is so sweet.
谢谢 你真应该看看她昨天的样子
Oh, thanks. Well, you should've seen her yesterday.
她直接把一个宝宝从小卡膝上推下去了
Yeah, she pushed a baby off of Cam's lap.
我知道 我知道
I know. I know.
她对小卡的占有欲太强了
She is so possessive of him, but, you know,
小卡正在努力不那么宠着她了
Cam's really working on trying not to coddle her so much,
所以
So...
我不觉得这和宠溺有关系
I'm not really sure it's about coddling.
更像是分享方面的问题
Sounds more like a sharing issue.
我们注意到莉莉不愿意与别人分享东西
You know, we've noticed Lily has a hard time with that.
-是吗 -我并不担心
- Really? - I wouldn't worry.
小孩子通常会从别的小孩身上学到
Kids usually pick that habit up from other kids,
也有些是从父母那里学到的
Except the ones that pick it up from their parents.
我们这有几个小孩子就是这样
We have a few of those in here.
当然 我不能告诉这些孩子的名字
Of course, I can't share those names with you...
除非我喝高了 酒后吐真言
until I get a glass of wine in my hand.
你真逗 伊莱恩小姐
Oh. Oh, Miss Elaine.
别人的确说过我可能有那么一丁点"分享障碍"
I have been told that I might have the teensiest issue with sharing.
但是莉莉真的是从我身上学到的吗
But is that something Lily would even pick up on?
我的鸡肉
My chicken.
我的枕头
My pillow.
爹地的笔
Daddy's pen.
好吧 有可能
Okay, it's possible.
为了莉莉 我应该改改了
And I suppose for Lily's sake, I-I should work on that...
偷偷地改 因为现在我们真的应该
privately. because right now we really need to
先搞定小卡的溺爱问题
get Cam's coddling problem under control.
怎么回事
What's going on?
搬到阁楼去睡
Moving into the attic.
给我一两天时间安定下来 我再请你上去坐坐
Give me a day or two to get settled, then I'll have you up.
你什么时候决定挪窝了
When did all this happen?
这要看你问谁了
Depends on who you ask.
我是已经觊觎了三周了
My plan's been in motion for three weeks.
亲爱的 这是个糟糕的主意 你会厌恶上面的
Honey, this is a terrible idea. You're gonna hate it up there.
妈妈 你别插手了
Mom, stay out of this.
现在我们都有自己的房间了 三赢
Yeah. We all have our own rooms now. Everybody wins.
不要太爽 女孩儿们
Well, don't get too comfortable in there, girls.
卢克 上面很冷 也很恐怖
Luke, it's cold, and it's scary up there.
你明天晚上就会回到自己房间的
You're gonna be back in your own room by tomorrow night.
我不明白 克莱尔 这里潜力无限
I don't know, Claire. It's got a lot of potential.
这个比我们相遇时我住的那个好多了
This is a lot nicer than the attic I lived in when we met.
相信我 再舒适他也最多坚持一晚
One night, if that. Trust me on this.
噢对啊 因为你永远是对的
Oh, yes, because you're always right.
孩儿们 我倒是想错一次
Sweetheart, I would love to be wrong.
但你们把错都犯完了 我想错都难啊
I just don't live with the right people for that.
算了吧 你妈是永不妥协的
Let it go, kids. She's not gonna budge.
-会唠叨我一晚上这事儿 -菲尔 的确是你推到我的
- Kept me up all night with the-- - Phil, you did push me!
你的说法跟我不一致
Your word against mine.
估计也很难搞清真相了 就像那些未解之谜
Guess it's one of those things we'll just never know,
好比泰坦尼克号沉没的真相
Like what really happened to the "Titanic."
泰坦尼克是撞冰山了
It hit an iceberg.
-或许吧 -必须的
- Maybe. - Mm, there's no maybe.
好吧 你是对的 克莱尔
Oh, you're right, Claire.
又对了哦
Again.
见怪不怪
Surprise, surprise.
好吧 我们一会儿在米奇尔舅舅家见
Okay, I-I will see you over at uncle Mitchell's.
我得逃离这个批斗克莱尔大会
I'm gonna skip this meeting of the pile-on Claire club.
估计也是我把她推到那个"大会"上的
Guess I pushed her into that pile, too.
我都等你们半辈子了
I spend half my life waiting on you.
你出门一次到底得换几次行头
How many times do you have to change your outfit?
抱歉杰 选择太多也是个烦恼
Sorry, Jay. Too many choices is a prison.
趁他还想换条裤子之前赶紧走
Just drive before he rethinks the pants.
-我裤子怎么了 -快 快
- What's wrong with my pants?! - Go. Go. Go.
曼尼 今天跟校长谈得如何
So, Manny, how'd it go with the principal today?
不是很好 但儿子很勇敢 都过去了
It was terrible, but he was brave, and now it's over.
-对吧 宝贝儿 -没错
- Right, Manny? - Mm-hmm.
-那个 -他们让你罚站还是停课
- So d-- - what'd they give you? Detention? Suspension?
没有 因为是初犯只给了警告
No, just a warning because it was first offense.
-今天工作如何啊 -挺好的
- So how was work? - Great.
只给了警告 是吧
Just a warning, huh?
我妈说得没错
Like she said.
我问你工作 你就给我打岔
So I ask about work, and you change the subject.
是不是瞒着我什么
Are you trying to hide something?
没有啊 我只想确保孩子没事 你没事吧
No, I just wanna make sure he's okay. You okay?
我就是有点疑惑 你怎么汗如雨下的
'cause, I mean, it looks like you're sweatin' bullets back there, kid.
别逼他了 先是校长 又是你
Stop grilling him. First the principal, now you.
这个可怜的孩子被折磨了一整天
This poor boy has been screamed at all day.
-更别提 -闭嘴 我正掌控全局呢
- Well, not to mention-- - Quiet! I've got this.
-莉莉呢 -她在穿衣服
- Where is Lily? - Um, she's getting dressed.
自己穿吗
All by herself?
-小卡正在鼓励她更独立 -原来如此
- Cam is encouraging her to be more independent. - Oh.
小公主驾到
And there she is!
美极了吧
Doesn't she look beautiful?
她就像沾完了胶水
She looks like she was dipped in glue,
然后从跳蚤市场里拖出来的
and dragged through a flea market.
-大家好 -来了啊
- Hey there! - Hi!
-快进来 开胃菜准备好了 -大家好吗
- Guys. Come on in. There's hors d'oeuvres. - How's it going?
你们家有旧家具吗
Hey, do you guys have any old furniture?
我正要搬到阁楼住
I'm moving into the attic.
-住阁楼吗 -至少足够大
- The attic? - Hey, at least it's big.
外公说你以前住柜子里[同性恋隐瞒性取向]
Grandpa said you used to live in the closet.
好吧 听我说
Okay. Well, you know what?
我们会给你找些家具用的
Yeah, we'll absolutely find you something for sure. Okay?
爸爸是我的
My daddy!
莉莉 别这样
Lily, no!
卢克 抱歉
I-I'm sorry, Luke.
这事没完
This isn't over.
天呐 小米 她越来越放肆了
Oh, my god. Mitchell, she's getting worse.
我把她变成了一个放肆无礼的小怪物
I have turned her into a pushy, little, entitled monster,
她将来肯定会被逮捕 被戴上脚铐的
on her way to a rap sheet and a bracelet on her ankle.
不是吧 她已经戴上脚铐了
Oh, she has a bracelet on her ankle.
小卡
Cam.
小卡 冷静
Cam, Cam.
这或许不全是你的责任
This--this might not be entirely your fault.
还能是谁的
No, it is.
我跟莉莉的老师谈过了
I spoke with Lily's teacher.
老师觉得她可能有分享障碍
And she thinks that--that she may have a problem with sharing,
她可能是从什么人身上学的...
Which she might have gotten from--
就是你啊 你不愿与人分享
You. You don't like to share.
不 我有时那样做是想说明某个道理
No, I do it to make a point sometimes.
比如 你想吃鸡肉 就自己点啊
Like, if you want the chicken, then order the chicken.
等一下 你什么时候去跟莉莉老师谈的
Wait, when did you talk to Lily's teacher?
今天 我送她上学时候
Uh, today, when I--when I dropped her off at school.
然后你居然让我自责了一整天
And you let me suffer all day?
我错了 但我们不能在大伙儿面前说这些吧
All right, look, we--we can't do this with everybody here.
-至少过了今晚再说 -好吧
- Can we please just get through the evening? - Yes,
但我们今晚不宣布领养孩子的事儿了
but we are not making the announcement tonight.
因为那本应是件高兴的事情
Because that is a joyful thing,
但我现在极为不高兴
And I am not feeling very joyful right now.
好吧 我分享到[感受到]你的怒火了
Well, I share your feeling.
告诉你吧 我看出你的把戏了
Just so you know, I'm on to you.
你根本没带曼尼去找校长
You never took Manny to the principal.
你继续装 但我了解曼尼
Okay, play it like that, but I know Manny.
他比你有良知
He has more of a conscience than you have.
他没法忍受良心受到谴责的
He's not gonna be able to live with this.
杰 别小看良心的承受能力
You'd be surprised what people can live with, Jay.
莉莉小公主 你好吗
Hi, Miss Lily. How's my big girl doing?
很好
Good.
告诉我 你今年几岁了
Can you tell me how old you are now?
那表示四岁 这是三岁
That's 4. This is 3.
来 再说一次 你几岁了
Okay, show me again. How old are you?
-三岁 -不对 那是四岁
- 3. - No! That many is 4.
这才是三岁
This many is 3.
别争了莉莉 你说不过她的
Don't argue, Lily. You'll never win.
是吗 菲尔
Really, Phil?
好吧 我本来打算回家再放这个的
Okay, I-I was gonna wait until we got home for this,
但现在我决定让大家分享这个开心一刻
But now I think it's something everyone's gonna enjoy.
大伙儿都到客厅来
Guys, everybody, come on down to the TV room.
给你们看个精彩的真人秀
I've got something really special to share.
每人来点喝的吗
Okay, how's everybody on drinks?
如果又像上次艾丽克斯毕业典礼那样 给我一整瓶吧
If this is Alex's graduation again, just leave me the bottle.
我不要了 小卡
I'm good, Cam.
大家就坐了
Okay, everybody.
好戏开始
Showtime.
我靠 居然是那天在超市的录像
Oh, my gosh. It's us at the market.
-你怎么搞到的 -没错 超市监控录像
- How did you-- - Yeah, it's security camera footage.
我不明白 我们要看什么
I don't understand. What are we watching?
我可以跟你说 绝对不是《教父》
It ain't "The godfather," I can tell you that much.
好的 听着 我昨天在商场里跌倒了
Okay, look, I fell yesterday at the market,
菲尔跟我在责任问题上
And Phil and I have been having a little disagreement
持不同意见 看着 就是这儿
as to what happened. Just watch. Okay, right here.
我停下来去整理鞋子 然后菲尔
I stop to fix my shoe, and then Phil--
在那里 好的
right there. Okay.
他给一位漂亮的女士让路
He makes way for this very attractive woman,
在他的叙述中 他把这段艳遇省略了
whom he conveniently leaves out of his retelling of the story.
就在这时 菲尔往后退了一步
Now right here, Phil backs up,
屁股撞到了购物车
pushes his butt into the cart,
让我撞到了那一堆罐头上
pushes me into the cans!
看到了没
Do you see that?! Oh!
都是他的错 就跟我说的一样
It's all his fault, just like I said!
我才是对的 去死吧
I was right! Suck it!
-你什么时候拿到的 -我的天呐
- When did you get this-- - Oh, my god.
这就是为什么你想单独过来
That's why you wanted to come separately.
你搞得那么麻烦就为了证明你是对的
You went to all that trouble just to prove you were right?
其实也没那么麻烦
It really wasn't that much trouble.
我只是到商场 找到你的朋友乔丹
I just went to the store, found your friend Jordan the bag boy,
他帮我找到了经理
who got me the manager.
他给了我远程安保室的地址
He gave me the address of the off-site security office.
我填了几张表 萨利把它传真到公司
I filled out some paperwork. Sally faxed it to corporate.
三分钟后我买了张DVD 刻了一张碟
Three minutes later, I'm buying pack of dvds and burning a copy.
小事一桩
Cake.
疯狂到病态啊
It's like a sickness.
干嘛 谁叫你们都不信我
What? None of you believed me,
我只好自证清白咯
so I got proof.
你们现在都去死吧
You should all be sucking it right now.
你能别再说"去死"好吗 克莱尔
Hey, please stop with the "Sucking it," Claire.
孩子都在呢
The children!
没错 孩子们非常容易受影响
Yes, children are very impressionable.
你永远不知道他们会捡什么学
You'll never know what they'll pick up.
小卡 我很抱歉把责任都归咎到你身上
Okay, cam, I'm sorry that I blamed it on you, okay?
但是我们的一言一行都得注意
But we both need to look at our actions.
如果我们想再领养一个孩子的话
I mean, if we're thinking about adopting another baby,
我们需要...
then we need to--
-你们 -你们要再领养一个
- You guys... - You're adopting another kid?
-不不不 -你们 等等 恭喜
- No! No, no! - You're--wait! Congratulations!
我们还在考虑 还没...
We're thinking about it. It's not...
到底发生什么事了
What the hell's happening here?
是《浑身是劲》的插曲吗
Is that from "Footloose"?
不是吧 米奇尔
Really, Mitchell?
你都不肯和我分享一起宣布消息
You couldn't even share telling your family!
行 行
Fine. Fine.
但你怎么这么郁闷呢 这是个好消息
But why are you upset? This is such good news.
不 我们只是有点担心
No, we're a little on edge
因为莉莉最近表现出
because lily has been acting out
她不想要兄弟姐妹
like she doesn't want a sibling, and--
没错 因为米奇尔把她教的不懂分享
Yeah, because Mitchell taught her to hate sharing.
或是因为小卡片刻不离地把她"戴"在身边
And/or because cam wears her like a fanny pack.
不要再互相责怪了
Oh, stop blaming each other.
没有孩子喜欢有兄弟姐妹
No kid wants a sibling.
克莱尔小时候就非常不待见你
I mean, Claire hated you so much
你两岁时她把你塞进了烘干机里
She stuck you in a dryer when you were 2.
你把我塞进烘干机里
You put me in the dryer?
没错 但不是因为我不喜欢你
I did, but it wasn't 'cause I hated you.
我朋友玛琪说
My friend Marci said
烘干机里面有孩子是无法起动的
That it wouldn't run with a kid inside it,
但我知道它会 事实证明我是对的
and I knew it would. I was right.
主啊
Good governor.
你五岁的时候就这样了
It's been going on since you were 5?
-天啊 真是扭曲病态啊 -你才知道
- Oh, my god. It is a sickness. -Yeah.
是什么让我那么小就这么扭曲了
What would make me have that need at such a young age?
我在那烘干机里呆了多久 因为我
How long was I in that dryer? Because I--
我是因此才那么害怕翻跟头吗
Is this why I'm afraid of tumbling?
我不得不退出体操队 克莱尔
I had to quit gymnastics, Claire!
一个没有翻跟斗的童年
A childhood without tumbling?
你知道这些 却只是旁观不语
You knew this and just stood by and did nothing?!
好了好了 木已成舟
Okay, okay. What's done is done!
你们能做的就是从中吸取教训
All you can do is learn from your mistakes.
本着这种精神
And in that spirit,
我要敬曼尼一杯
I would like to propose a toast... to Manny.
这周他做了一件本不该做的事
This week, he did something he wasn't supposed to do,
-就跟我们一样 -就跟我们一样
- like we all do-- - Like we all do!
-敬曼尼 -等等
- Salud to Manny! - Uh, not yet.
但是曼尼男子汉似的站出来
But Manny stood up like a man.
他承认了错误 并且接受了惩罚
He admitted he was wrong and he took his licks,
我为他感到自豪
and I'm damn proud of him.
现在干杯
Ah, now we clink!
不 只有我说干杯时才干杯
No, we clink when I say we clink.
曼尼犯了错 但是他却没有逃避
So Manny made a mistake, but he didn't take the easy way out.
他很勇敢 正直善良
He's got guts, he's got integrity.
就我所知 他是最棒的小...
As far as I'm concerned, he's the best little b--
够了 停停 你说的我都没做
Okay, stop! Stop! I didn't do any of that.
老妈撬开了柜子把吊坠扔回去了
Mom broke into the locker and threw the necklace inside,
然后我们像胆小鬼一样溜走了
and then we ran away like cowards.
-对不起 杰 对不起 -我就知道
- I'm sorry, jay! I'm sorry! - I knew it!
我是对的 我是对的
I was right! I was right!
谁
Who is it?
亲爱的 是我 你还好吗
Hi, honey. It's just me. Are you okay?
我很好
Yeah. I'm great.
喜欢你的新居吗
So, how you liking your new digs?
我知道你说这上面会很冷
I know you told me that I'd be cold...
我会被吓坏
and scared...
-但你错了 -是的 我看得出来
- But I'm not. - No, I can see that.
是我错了
I was--I was wrong.
-是你错了 -是的
- You were. - Yeah.
那么接下来你肯定非常不喜欢了 亲爱的
Well, you're gonna hate this then, honey,
我需要你下去 回你原来的房间去
but I'm gonna need you to go back down and sleep in your old room.
我怕你这么小就拥有
I just--I'm worried if you get something so cool
如此奇妙的体验
this early in your life,
你以后就没有什么可以期待的了
You're not gonna have anything to look forward to later.
我现在就得下去吗
I-I have to go now?
如果你想的话你也可以在这里过夜
You can spend the night tonight here if you want.
不了 如果这对你那么重要
Oh! No, if it's so important to you,
我现在就下去
I'll go now.
你也应该下去
You should come, too.
有什么东西在那里
Something sleeps over there.
等等我 等等我
Wait for me. Wait. Wait for me! Wait for me.